翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
The last operation we need to implement is removeLast.
我们要实现的最后一个操作是 removeLast
Now, before we do this, I actually want to take a step back and think carefully about the user's mental model.
在这之前，我想退一步好好思考一下用户的心理模型
What is it we're trying to capture?
我们要捕获什么？
So let's imagine the user has inserted, as far as they're concerned, 5, 3, 1, 7, 22,
假设用户插入5、3、1、7、22
and then, finally, they called addLast minus 1.
最后调用 addLast(-1)
They've built this list.
建立了链表
So this is more or less what the user is thinking about.
这或多或少就是用户所想的
Now the user calls remove last, and what do we expect?
现在用户调用 removeLast，我们期待什么呢？
Well, we expect that minus goes away.
预计-1会消失
That's the mental model that the user is thinking about.
这就是用户正在考虑的心理模型
Now, our job as the implementer of this abstract data type, of this list,
作为这个抽象数据类型链表的实现者
is that it needs to behave the way the user wants to
需要使它按照用户希望的方式运行
and, beyond that, it doesn't matter what we do, as long as the behavior is correct.
除此之外一切无关紧要，只要我们的行为是正确的
So in this approach, our concrete reality,
在这种方式下，我们的具体现实
the actual truth that we have designed,
我们设计的实际情况
is to use this array to hold all the information.
就是使用这个数组来存储所有信息
And at this moment, our goal is to manipulate this concrete reality to match the user's abstract mental model.
此时我们的目标是操纵这个具体的现实，使之与用户的抽象心理模型相匹配
Now, there are many ways we could have done it.
我们有很多方法可以做到这一点
In fact, in the previous lecture,
事实上在上一节课中
the actual truth looked nothing like this at all.
实际情况看起来根本不是这样
There was a DList that was a recursively defined data structure.
DList 是递归定义的数据结构
We did all that work for that, and it was a totally different way of implementing it.
我们为此做了所有的工作，实现方式完全不同
But as far as the user was concerned,
但是对于用户而言
the behavior was exactly the same.
它们的行为完全一样
There's actually a lot of parallels with Plato's Allegory of the Cave from 2,500 years ago.
这与2500年前柏拉图的“洞穴寓言”有很多相似之处
So the user, the person using the list data structure here,
用户，也就是使用链表数据结构的人
they basically have a specific reality that they can see,
他们基本上有一个能看到的具体现实
that hopefully they can actually interact with,
他们可以与之交互
and it behaves in a way that makes sense.
并且它的行为方式是有意义的
We, by contrast, are these monks.
相比之下，我们是这些僧侣
We're the implementers.
我们是实现者
We're one level of abstraction up,
抽象程度上升了一级
and our job is to manipulate these little figures
我们的工作就是操纵这些小图案
so that the show they're seeing actually matches what they expect.
这样他们所见才能真正符合预期
And if they try to shoot this thing with their finger, like shoot the bird,
如果他们试图用手指射杀这个东西，比如射杀那只鸟
then this guy's job is to lower the bird
那这个人就把鸟放下来
and show that the bird has been defeated or whatever.
表明这只鸟已经被打败了什么的
Now, unlike Plato's Allegory of the Cave,
与柏拉图的“洞穴寓言”不同
where we might imagine using our knowledge to divine the nature of reality and climb out and be free,
在那里我们可以想象用我们的知识来占卜现实的本质，然后爬出洞穴获得自由
we do not want to do that as programmers.
作为程序员，我们不想这样做
The person in the cave does not care about the world out here.
山洞里的人并不关心外面的世界
And in fact, a lot of the progress in computer science
事实上，计算机科学的许多进步
is being willfully ignorant about the outside world.
就是故意对外面的世界一无所知
That's one of the glorious things about Java.
这是 Java 的光荣之处
For example, the private keyword says, no, this world is forbidden to you.
例如 private 关键字禁止你通向这个世界
You are not allowed to see it.
不许你看
And that makes it easier to live the life that you want.
这会让你更容易过上想要的生活
So that said, let's imagine trying to write removeLast.
让我们想象一下尝试编写 removeLast
So as the manipulator's reality,
作为操纵者的现实
as those who are charged with changing the concrete representation to match the abstract,
作为那些负责改变具体表象以配合抽象的人
what memory boxes actually need to change?
究竟需要改变哪些内存盒子？
Now, one thing I'm going to mention is that the invariance that we've created here,
我要提到的一件事是，我们在这里创造的不变量
they actually provide us with a guide.
实际上为我们提供了指导
There are a set of rules that these characters here can use to manipulate the figures to match the expectations of the user.
演员通过这些规则可以用来操纵图案，以符合用户的期望
And as long as we follow these, we should be in good shape.
只要我们遵循这些，就会保持良好的状态
So all of that said, some philosophy aside,
说了这么多，抛开哲学不谈
try and imagine what memory boxes need to change,
试着想象一下需要改变哪些内存盒子
and I'll wait here and let you ponder it.
我等你好好考虑一下
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）